Finding Aid for the John Egerton Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- REACH Project-Research and Background Materials-Handwritten Notes (Box 19, Folder 9)
- REACH Project-Research and Background Materials-Project Directors’ Meetings (Box 19, Folder 10)
- REACH Project-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Common College (1974)-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Common College-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Common College-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Common College-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 19, Folder 15)
- American History Study Guide (1975)
  - Manuscript (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Typescript drafts of manuscript (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Planning and Outlines (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Clippings (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Handwritten Notes (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-8 Audio Tapes-Interviews with C. Vann Woodward and John Hope Franklin (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Bibliography Notes (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Pringles vs. the Real Thing (1975)-Manuscript (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Pringles vs. the Real Thing-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Pringles vs. the Real Thing-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 21, Folder 3)
- The Futures Of Children (Vanderbilt University Institute for Public Policy Studies, 1975)-Manuscript (Box 21, Folder 4)
- The Futures of Children- Research and Background Materials-Interviews/Articles (Box 21, Folder 5)
- The Futures of Children- Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 21, Folder 6)
- The Futures of Children-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Classifying Children (Children Today, July/August, 1975)-Manuscript (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Equality of Access in Postsecondary Education (The Southern Education Foundation & The Ford Foundation, 1975)-Manuscript (Box 21, Folder 9)
- West Virginia School Textbook Controversy (The Progressive, 1975)-Typescript of article (Box 21, Folder 10)
- West Virginia School Textbook Controversy-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 21, Folder 11)
- West Virginia School Textbook Controversy-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 21, Folder 12)
- West Virginia School Textbook Controversy-Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Articles (Box 21, Folder 13)
- West Virginia School Textbook Controversy-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 21, Folder 14)
- West Virginia School Textbook Controversy-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Unemployment in Nashville (1975)-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Unemployment in Nashville-Research and Background Materials-Articles-(Unemployment Nationwide) (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Unemployment in Nashville-Research and Background Materials-Articles-(Unemployment Nationwide) (Box 21, Folder 18)
- Unemployment in Nashville-Research and Background Materials-Articles-(Unemployment in Nashville) (Box 21, Folder 19)
- Unemployment in Nashville-Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Clippings (Box 21, Folder 20)
- American Life (1976)
  - Planning and Outlines (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Research and Background Materials-Handwritten Notes (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Research and Background Materials-Diary of Egerton’s trip through the Northeastern States (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Magazines (Bicentennial Editions) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Clippings (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Newspapers (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Brochures, Maps (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Brochures, Maps (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Research and Background Materials-Taped interview with Sue Alston, Hampton Plantation and miscellaneous tapes made while traveling (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C. (1976)-typescript of article for New York Times Magazine (unpublished) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Planning and Outlines (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Articles (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-Handwritten Notes (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-Statistical Data (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-Federal Court Cases (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Research and Background Materials-John Norton-Private Schools in South Carolina: A Case Study (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Private Education in Columbia, S.C.-Publication Materials-Contracts (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Airlie House Conference on Higher Education (1976)-Manuscripts-Essays by Perrachio, Otten, and Murphy (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Airlie House Conference-Planning (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Airlie House Conference-Conference Schedules (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Airlie House Conference-Research and Background Materials-Egerton’s Handwritten Notes (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Airlie House Conference-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - The Peoples of the South: Heritages and Futures-A Regional Conference on Humanities and Public Policy (1976)-Manuscript (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - The Peoples of the South: Heritages and Futures -Egerton’s taped interviews with Participants at the regional conference (Box 23, Folder 21)
- School Desegregation: A Report Card from the South (1976)
  - Manuscript (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Chapter drafts (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Planning and Outlines (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Articles (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Data from Specific School Systems (Anniston, Alabama; Charlotte-Mecklenburg, North Carolina; Hillsborough City, Florida; Little Rock, Arkansas; Metro Nashville, Tennessee; Meridian, Mississippi; Williamsburg City, South Carolina (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Pierre Conference (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Research and Background Materials-Responses to Coleman Report (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Research and Background Materials-Critique of Coleman Report (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Publication Materials-Abstract of Report by Anna Durham (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Project for Teacher Improvement (Change, 1976-77)-Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interview (G.C. Jernstedt) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interview (Richard Pride) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interview (Ruth Jacobs) (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (General) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Jernstedt) (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Pride) (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Jacobs) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Back to Basics (The Progressive, 1976)-Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Back to Basics-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Back to Basics-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Back to Basics-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Back to Basics-Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Articles (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Back to Basics-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Tennessee’s Long-Running Desegregation Drama (The Chronicle of Higher Education, April 1977)-Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Fannie Lou Hamer (The Progressive, May 1977)-Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Lancelot by Walker Percy-A Book Review for The Progressive, June 1977-Manuscript (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - A Chance to Learn: A History of Race and Education in the United States by Meyer Weinberg-A Book Review for The Progressive, October 1977 (Box 25, Folder 19)
- Visions of Utopia (1977)
  - Manuscript (2 copies) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript (Excerpts printed in Southern Exposure and The Progressive) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Galley Proofs (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Planning and Outlines (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Handwritten Notes (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Clippings (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Research and Background Materials-Photographs (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Printed Materials (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Visions of Utopia (1977)-Publication Materials-Contracts & Related Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Visions of Utopia-Reviews (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Visions of Utopia-Videotape (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Eckerd College- (Change, 1977)-Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Eckerd College-Research and Background Materials-Interviews, including 2 tapes (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Eckerd College-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Eckerd College-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Eckerd College-Research and Background Materials-Articles by Billy Wireman, President of Eckerd College (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Eckerd College-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Eckerd College-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Homecoming (New Times, July 1977)-Manuscript (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Homecoming-Galley Proofs (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Homecoming-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Homecoming-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Homecoming-Research and Background Materials-Photographs (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Homecoming- Correspondence-Incoming (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - The Death of Elvis Presley (1977)-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - The Death of Elvis Presley-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - The Death of Elvis Presley-Research and Background Materials-Commemorative Newspaper (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Colonel Hawk of Bardstown, Kentucky (Louisville Courier-Journal Magazine, 1977)-Manuscript (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Colonel Hawk of Bardstown, Kentucky-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle (The Chronicle of Higher Education, 1977)-Manuscript (2 Copies) (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle-Manuscript of Consultant Report-The G.I. Bill.. .Changing Veterans’ Lives in Nashville (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle-Planning and Outlines (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle- Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - The Vietnam Era G.I. Bill: Boon or Boondoggle-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - As Jamaican as Apple Pie (The Progressive, 1977)-Manuscript (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - As Jamaican as Apple Pie-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - As Jamaican as Apple Pie-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools (Center for Equal Education, 1977)-Manuscript (2 Copies) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Planning and Outlines (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Gratton School, San Francisco, California (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Manual High School, Denver, Colorado) (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Miami Carol Senior High School, Opa Locka, Florida) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Miami Chapel & Louise Troy, Dayton, Ohio and English High School, Boston, Massachusetts (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Amory Middle School, Amory, Mississippi (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Trigg City High School, Cadiz, Kentucky) (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Head School, Nashville, Tennessee) (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Education and Desegregation in Eight Schools-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Humanities Seminars for Medical Practitioners-1977-Planning and Outlines for Proposed article (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Humanities Seminars for Medical Practitioners-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Humanities Seminars for Medical Practitioners-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Humanities Seminars for Medical Practitioners-Research and Background Materials-Conference Materials for Seminar at Vanderbilt University, July 11-Aug.5, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Humanities Seminars for Medical Practitioners-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - The King Coal Good Times Blues (New Times, 1978)-Manuscript (2 Copies) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - The King Coal Good Times Blues-Galley Proof (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - The King Coal Good Times Blues-Typescript of Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - The King Coal Good Times Blues-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - The King Coal Good Times Blues-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - The King Coal Good Times Blues-Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Clippings (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - The King Coal Good Times Blues-Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - The King Coal Good Times Blues-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Reflections on a Word Bank (The Progressive, July 1978)-Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Brother to a Dragonfly by Will Campbell-A Book Review for The Progressive, February, 1978 -Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Looks Like the Mason-Dixon Line Was Erased (The New York Times, May 1978)-Manuscript (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Needs-A Position Paper for the Tennessee Conference on Library and Information Services (1978)-Planning and Outlines (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Needs-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Needs-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute (1978)-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Southern Exposure-1978-A Proposal for a Magazine to be Titled Kudzu (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - The Trial of Highlander (Southern Exposure, 1978)-Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - The Trial of Highlander-Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - The Trial of Highlander-Research and Background Materials-Articles (Legal Documents) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - The Trial of Highlander-Research and Background Materials-Newspaper Articles about the trial (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - The Trial of Highlander-Research and Background Materials-Article About Highlander (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - The Trial of Highlander-Research and Background Materials-Publications By Highlander (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - The Trial of Highlander-Research and Background Materials-Articles About the Appalachian Region (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - The Trial of Highlander-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - What Does Will Campbell Do In a Year? (The Tennessean, Oct. 19, 1979)-Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Low Cost Housing (Southern Exposure, 1979)-Planning and Outlines (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Low Cost Housing-Research and Background Materials-Articles & Notes (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Low Cost Housing-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Last Train to Nashville (1979)-Manuscript (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Last Train to Nashville-Research and Background Materials-Articles & Notes (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Last Train to Nashville-Correspondence-Incoming (Box 31, Folder 151)
- A Gentleman’s Fight (American Heritage, 1979)
  - Manuscript (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Typescript of draft of article (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Planning and Outlines (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interviews (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Research and Background Materials-Handwritten Research Notes (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Publication Materials-Contract (Box 32, Folder 9)
- Nashville: The Faces of Two Centuries (1979)
  - Manuscript-Final Galley Proofs-Section I (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript-Final Galley Proofs-Section II (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript- Final Galley Proofs Section III (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript-Final Galley Proofs-Section IV (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript-Final Galley Proofs-Section V (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript-Printer’s Proof-Section I (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript-Printer’s Proof-Section II (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript-Printer’s Proof-Section III (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript-Printer’s Proof-Section IV (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Manuscript-Printer’s Proof-Section V (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Manuscript-Typescript-Section I (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript-Typescript-Section II (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript-Typescript-Section III (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript-Typescript-Section IV (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript-Typescript-Section V (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript-Typescript of Word Pictures, Sections I & II (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript-Typescript 0f Word Pictures, Sections III, IV, & V (Box 33, Folder 17)
- Nashville: The Faces of Two Centuries (1979)
  - Manuscript-Typescript and Galley Proofs of Cutlines, Section I (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript-Typescript and Galley Proofs of Cutlines, Section II (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript-Typescript and Galley Proofs of Cutlines, Section III (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript-Typescript and Galley Proofs of Cutlines, Section IV (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript-Typescript of Cutlines, Section V (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript-Typescript of Essays for Sections I, II, III. & V (Dykeman, Smith, Franklin and Grantham) (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript-Typescript of Essay for Section IV (Robert Penn Warren) (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Planning and Outlines (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Research and Background Materials-Interview and Tapes (Robert Penn Warren) (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Research and Background Materials-Articles (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence-Outgoing (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence-Incoming (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Reviews (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Promotional Materials (Box 34, Folder 14)
- See Box 89 for Oversized Proofs of Nashville: The Faces of Two Centuries
- Subject Files (1970s)
- Integrated Education: Race and Schools
  - May-June, 1972, Vol. X, No. 3 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - July-August, 1972. Vol. X, No. 4 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - September-October, 1972, Vol. X, No. 5 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - November-December, 1972, Vol. X, No. 6 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - January-February, 1973, Vol. XI, No. 1 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - March-April, 1973, Vol. XI, No. 2 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - May-June, 1973, Vol. IX, No. 3 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - July-October, 1973, Vol. XI, No. 4 & 5 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - November-December, 1973, Vol. XI, No. 6 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - January-April, 1974, Vol. XII, No. 1-2 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - May-June, 1974, Vol. XII, No. 3 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - July-August, 1974, Vol. XII, No. 4 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - September-October, 1974, Vol. XII, No. 5 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - November-December, 1974, Vol. XII, No. 6 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - January-February, 1975, Vol. XIII, No. 1 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - May-June, 1975, Vol. XIII, No. 3 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - July-August, 1975, Vol. XIII, No. 4 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - September-October, 1975, Vol. XIII, No. 5 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - November-December, 1975, Vol. XIII, No. 6 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - January-February, 1976, Vol. XIV, No. 1 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - March-April, 1976, Vol. XIV, No. 2 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - May-June, 1976, Vol. XIV, No. 3 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - July-August, 1976, Vol. XIV, No. 4 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - September-October, 1976, Vol. XIV, No. 5 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - November-December, 1976, Vol. XIV, No. 6 (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - January-February, 1977, Vol. XV, No. 1 (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - March-April, 1977, Vol. XV, No. 2 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - May-June, 1977, Vol. XV, No. 3 (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - July-August, 1977, Vol. XV, No.4 (Box 35, Folder 29)
- Subject Files (1970s)
  - Cairo, Illinois: Racism at Floodtide, Oct. 1973-Report of the U. S. Commission on Civil Rights (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Toward Quality Education for Mexican-Americans, Feb. 1974-Report of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - A Better Chance to Learn: Bilingual-Bicultural Education, May, 1975-Report of the U. S. Commission on Civil Rights (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - The State of Civil Rights: 1977-Report of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Indian Education, Inequality in Education, # 7, February 1971 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Special Report: Drugs, Discipline, & Disruption, Inequality in Education, # 8, June, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - School Desegregation in 1971, Inequality in Education, # 9, August 1971 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Symposium on Indian Education, Inequality in Education, # 10, December 1971 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Perspectives on Busing, Inequality in Education, # 11, March 1972 (Box 36, Folder 9)